My name is Happy Gilmore.
Growing up, I always
wanted to be a hockey player.
But then 30 years ago,
I picked up a golf club.
[yelps]
Turned out to be a pretty good decision.
[commentator] And Happy Gilmore wins
the 98th U.S. Open.
[Happy] I got to marry
a great lady named Virginia,
and we had a son named Gordy.
The wins didn't always come as expected,
but like Grandma always said,
sometimes it's better
to be lucky than good.
- Oh, Lord!
- [crowd cheering]
I made it!
Yeah, I was getting lucky
in more ways than one.
He shoots, he scores!
And after our fourth boy in four years,
Virginia had an idea for an endorsement.
Trojan. Kids are great...
[kids screaming]
...in moderation.
What are you doing? Calm down!
I tried to get the boys
into competitive golf tournaments...
Follow that.
[Happy] But their hockey instincts
were too strong.
[indistinct shouting]
Boys, stop! Come on,
what are you doing? [groans]
[boys shouting indistinctly]
[Happy] Tiger Woods had a video game,
so we did a Happy Gilmore one.
But I think the computer guys
made it a little too realistic.
[Bob] You've had enough.
[Happy] Anyways, the boys loved
how violent it was,
but it made my little girl nervous.
That's right,
we finally had a little girl,
sweet Vienna, Mommy's new best friend.
Oh, and I hosted Saturday Night Live
a few times. That was nice.
The Spice Girls are here!
Maroon 5 is here!
The Weeknd is here!
So stick around, we'll be right back.
Yeah, we had it all, so I told Virginia...
We should just retire
so we can hang out with the kids all day.
We're not done with golf, Happy.
And golf's not done with us.
It's like Chubbs used to say.
We've only just begun.
Hmm.
[Bobby] Gordy!
Oh, come on,
don't pee on the slip-n-slide.
Appreciate your time today.
It's Mother's Day.
We honor all of the mothers
who are watching.
Let's go real deep now!
But in golf,
even when you're at the top of your game...
you can always shank one.
[gasps]
- [thuds]
- [crowd groan]
[softly] Uh-oh.
After the funeral, I decided
I would never pick up a golf club again.
I was now
a single father of five children.
There was really
only one thing I could do...
I'd never been a big boozer,
but alcohol was the only thing
that helped me
to forget what I'd done
to the sweetest woman I'd ever known.
-Oh, one more thing...
- It's no good.
- [Happy] The money.
- [bottles clinking]
Give me the...
No, no, dude! Come on, man.
[Happy] See, Virginia always handled
the finances,
so without her,
a lot of stuff fell through the cracks.
[man] Should I smash the window?
[Happy] Then I caught some guy
trying to break into my Ferrari.
Hey, can you hold my beer?
Yeah. [grunts]
The guy wasn't a thief, he was a repo man.
[man] Can you let me explain?
[Happy] Turns out I didn't know
I had to renew the lease.
The big baby sued me,
and I lost everything...
including Grandma's house,
which was devastating.
The boys had to
move into an apartment together,
and me and Vienna
found a new place that was affordable.
It's not the best neighborhood,
but it's walkable to my new job.
[woman over PA]
Gary, can you pick up in section 2?
[music playing indistinctly over speakers]
[gulping, sighs]
Happy Gilmore.
Oh, my God, I'm such a massive fan.
Okay, bro, what can I help you with?
You ever hear of Maxi Sports Drink?
I think that's aisle four.
No. It's my company, I own it.
I'm Frank Manatee.
My real passion is this cutting-edge
golf project that I've been working on.
[sighs] I don't golf no more, brother.
Cucumber juice in there?
Sure.
Anyway, I figured
maybe you would start golfing again
once you heard
how huge this league was gonna be.
I wish you luck, but I'm not interested.
See, that's the thing.
Nobody's interested in traditional golf.
It's a boring sport
played by boring people.
They ain't boring, they're my friends.
You don't understand.
You inspired this thing, all right?
And I love you,
and I'd hate to see you pass this up
and have your life turn out
worse than it already is.
I get it. Golf makes you tense, right?
Because the whole wife thing?
Get your skunk breath
out of my face, or I swear to God--
Or what, tough guy?
You're not gonna do a damn thing about it,
because if you lay one finger on me,
you're going right to jail.
That's if I get caught.
[Linda] Operations.
Hey, Linda, can you turn
the security cameras off for 90 seconds?
[indistinct muffled shouting]
[muffled screaming]
Seven, eight. Fouetté, fouetté. Finish.
Great. Arms, fifth. Soutenu.
Fouetté, fouetté.
Arms, fifth.
Soutenu. Chaîné, chaîné.
And arabesque.
Look at that.
- Daddy!
- [chuckles]
[Happy] Hey, Vienna.
Oh, with the kicks!
Hey. The Rockettes are here.
[Vienna] Glad you're home.
You were a clue on Jeopardy!
Let me show you.
Really?
Okay. Hi.
Hi.
How'd my girl do today?
Great. Beyond great.
She needs a better teacher than me.
- Look.
- [Happy] Yeah.
[Ken] With his amazing long drives
and hockey player's temper,
this golfer won the first of his six
Tour Championships in 1996. Carter?
Who is Happy Goldberg?
[Ken] Sorry, no. Ling.
Who is Happy Gudenstein?
[Ken] Nope. Jana.
Who is Skippy Goldenbaum?
- [buzzer sounds]
- That is incorrect.
He is Jewish,
but we were looking for Happy Gilmore.
At least he knew it.
I'm making your grandma's
brisket for dinner.
The boys are coming.
Okay, good. Good, I can't wait.
What do you mean, a better teacher?
Are you quitting?
No, but I work at the Boys and Girls Club.
She's light years
beyond anyone else I ever taught.
So what? Where should she go?
The Paris Opera Ballet School.
Where's that? Around here?
- It's in Paris.
- [sighs]
They only have four slots open each year.
I sent them the videos of Vienna,
and they're saving
one of the slots for her.
Is it free?
How much is it?
$75,000 a year.
I marinated the brisket in ketchup all day
like you said Grandma used to.
Absolutely incredible.
You crushed it, Vivi.
Vienna, you're gonna
have to make more. I'm starving.
Easy, Bobby. Make your own.
- Terry, how about I make you cry?
- Are you freaking kidding?
- Yeah! Strangle him! Use it!
- [clamoring]
Put the fork down! Not the fork.
We fight in the basement,
not at the table.
- Sorry, Daddy.
- Sorry.
It's all right.
How's work going, boys?
I gotta say, Pop,
I'm loving the road crew.
[all laughing]
I'm killing it at the car wash.
I'm going for Employee of the Month
at the drugstore.
[laughing] Whoop, whoop, whoop.
I've been keeping the sky safe
at the airport.
- [all laughing]
- [loud thud]
Dude!
You guys wouldn't have to be working
if I didn't lose all our money.
- We don't need no money.
- Money's for snobs.
Everybody needs money
to chase their dreams.
You guys didn't even go to college
because you thought you had to
stick around here and keep an eye on me.
What are you talking about?
- ...we got brisket, we got hockey here.
- ...we got food.
I'm just psyched you thought
any of us could get into college.
[Terry] He's not going to college.
[Bobby] That's what he was talking about.
It's a turn of phrase. Not saying--
Turn of phrase? You just said--
[Gordy] Say your phrase.
[Bobby] It makes no sense.
[Gordy] I know what it means.
You turn and you look at somebody
and you say some-- [laughs]
♪ Here, it's never ending
Can't remember when it started ♪
♪ Pass around the lampshade
There'll be plenty enough room in jail ♪
[indistinct chatter]
♪ If being wrong's a crime
I'm serving forever ♪
♪ If being strong's your kind
I need help... ♪
I'm telling you now,
I'm getting the waterbed.
What are you talking about?
I shottied the waterbed.
- [Gordy] Enough out of you.
- [Bobby] What?
[Terry] You're on the floor.
You popped the waterbed.
- Come on, let's go.
- [Happy] All right.
- [Vienna] Night, guys. Love you.
- [Happy] Thanks for coming.
Call me when you get there.
Wait a minute. How are there four of you?
Wait a minute. Who's steering?
Gordy, don't steer with your feet.
Chips off the old block, huh?
[Vienna] Hey, Uncle John Daly.
Hey, Vienna, Happy.
Hey, pal.
I'm almost out of here.
I just put a down payment on a tent.
Will you stop? I don't want you to leave.
Stay as long as you need to.
I appreciate you.
You want to come watch Love Island?
I do, but I'm going to have
a couple of nightcaps
and get some rest for work tomorrow.
Make that scratch, dog.
Absolutely. Good night, my brother.
Night, night. Love you.
[Happy] Love you.
Oh, my God. I hope he marries her.
[woman on TV] She going for it.
I should be putting you to bed.
[grunts]
Look, Dad, I know Miss Simon
talked to you about dance school,
but don't even think about it.
When I was a teenager,
I wanted to be on the Bruins.
This is your Bruins.
Except you know how to dance
and I didn't know how to skate.
Did you know Mama was a great dancer?
[Vienna] Yeah, she was.
Get some sleep, Dad.
[Happy] Yeah, she was something else.
[Vienna] Good night, Dad.
Good night, Virginia.
I can't believe that me in cheap lingerie
carrying two pitchers of Moosehead
was your "happy place."
I'm sorry, Virginia.
Oh, sweetie, don't worry.
I'm not here to judge your fantasies.
No, not that. I'm sorry about...
Killing me with a tee shot?
Come on.
You've apologized for that
a thousand times.
Look, Happy, I know you're worried
about the kids' futures,
but you've got to show them by example.
Let them see
the Happy I fell in love with.
- I'm not that man anymore.
- Mmm.
Okay. No, no, no.
- Please.
- No, no.
Can you just hold on to that
for a second, sweetie?
Honey, you'll always be the greatest,
but you need some purpose.
So I'm gonna tell you
what I always told you.
Okay.
You're not a hockey player, Happy.
You are a--
Hey, where you going
with those clubs, punk?
Mr. Gilmore, I'm your caddie.
Oh, I'm sorry about that.
No, let me carry these.
They're my grandfather's. They're old.
[hopeful music plays]
[music intensifies]
[music stops]
You gonna hit that?
I don't know if I can, Johnny.
How are you gonna
put Vienna through ballet school?
You know about that?
Of course. You know what else I know?
It's $75,000 a year.
That's four years. That's 333 grand.
That's terrible math, Johnny.
It's 300 grand.
Hey, if you can get a discount,
that's great.
But how you gonna make that cha-ching?
I don't know.
I thought I'd pick a few double shifts
up at the supermarket. Maybe--
There's only one way you can make
some big dollars fast. Grip it and rip it.
Johnny, I wouldn't even know
where to start.
At the bottom.
Excuse me, I'm looking to get out there.
[man snores]
There's a threesome going out at 10:15.
You can join them. Name?
Don't worry about it.
I won't.
Who was that? Grizzly Adams?
I don't know who that is.
- [Steiner laughs]
- Is it just us three?
No. Starter said a fourth
is playing with us.
- We gotta play with some random?
- [Sally] Yup.
It's always some yin-yang
who plays like shit and never shuts up.
[Fitzy] Oh, man. Is that him?
He looks like he got a divorce
four seconds ago.
Are you the one that's playing with us?
I think so, yeah.
We like to play quick, so try to keep up?
Got it.
- Let's get this party started?
- [Sally] Yeah.
- [Fitzy] Yeah, let's get it started.
- Whoo!
[speaks Spanish]
Oh!
- [in English] Whoo! Cart path!
- Man!
- Nice one, Fitzy.
- Hell yeah.
- [Sally exclaims]
- I will take that all day.
[Steiner] Yes, sir.
You got this, girl. Get that shit.
[Steiner whistles] Ha!
Gotta be happy with that, Sal.
- Top spinner. Just how I drew it up, boys.
- Mmm-hmm.
Check this out. [exhales]
Xanax arms, head still.
Oh! [chuckles]
- [Sally] What the hell?
- [Fitzy] Holy shit.
[Steiner] Boom! Explosion!
That's my dog!
Mmm-hmm! Took a lesson at Golf Hut.
- It shows, Stein-man.
- [both] Uh-huh.
[both grunting triumphantly]
[exclaims triumphantly]
- [both chuckle]
- Man, I wish I was included in that.
- [Steiner] Boy.
- [Sally] He doing the Happy Gilmore swing?
My stupid uncle
always tries that bullshit.
Swings and misses every time.
Pain in my ass.
[yelps]
God. He rolled further than the ball.
[Fitzy] Gonna be a long-ass day, my dudes.
["Don Quichotte" playing]
[grunts]
- [whoops]
- [kisses]
Hell yeah!
Oh, eat a bag of--
Did you find your ball yet?
[Happy] Yeah, I found it.
I'm just roaming around in here because
I like poison ivy, you piece of--
Grandma!
- [shattering]
- Oh, choke on my dangling, wrinkly--
[yells]
[groans]
I don't know why,
I get so intimidated in the sand.
The dude from Golf Hut
said just flip it like a pancake.
- Flip that pancake, Sally.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Nice!
- [both exclaim]
♪ To the window, to the walls ♪
♪ To the walls ♪
♪ 'Til sweat drop down my balls ♪
♪ 'Til all these bitches crawl ♪
♪ 'Til all skeet-skeet, motherfucker ♪
♪ 'Til all skeet-skeet, goddamn ♪
♪ A-goddamn ♪
["Don Quichotte" resumes]
Nice putt, dude.
We'll put you down for a 12.
Yeah.
[sighs]
I think he thinks
the tee-marker's the ball.
[yelps]
Told you.
Hey, DJ Khaled, maybe give
the Happy Gilmore swing a rest?
Because it ain't working.
Yo, that is Happy Gilmore.
Happy Gilmore sucks?
[thuds]
Hey, can you call fore next time?
- [grunts]
- [shudders]
[laughs] Fore!
[laughing]
- [Happy grunting]
- [Steiner] Whoa.
Hey, man, at least it went in.
[Happy] It did?
[all] No! [laughing]
Man, Happy Gilmore
is such a joke. It's sad.
Still got to ask
for his autograph, though.
My auntie used to cream her jeans
for that fool.
- [laughs]
- Whoa!
[Happy] Tell your aunt I'll sign her jeans
for $300,000. [laughs]
I guess I'm a little rusty, gang.
The Stein-man recently had a lesson
at the Golf Hut.
Yes.
But I just, I haven't swung a club
in ten years, so, sorry.
[groans]
How about you, Chubbs?
You got any tips for me?
[Chubbs] Relax, do what we talked about.
It's all in the hips,
yeah, it's all in the hips!
It's all...
Oh, yeah. Ease the tension.
Oh. I miss you, baby.
My man having a wet dream
we don't know about?
[hopeful music plays]
[grunts]
[ball whizzing]
[all exclaiming]
- Oh, my God!
- Now that is some Happy Gilmore shit!
- Yes. Yeah.
- [Steiner] Unbelievable!
I mean, I've hit some big ones,
but that was a freakin' rocket!
It was, like, effortless,
but still ferocious.
You got to teach me how to do that, dude.
Dude! [yelling] Dude!
- Dude!
Remember Happy Gilmore?
He's making news on the golf course again.
And not the good kind.
He was apparently driving a golf cart
while intoxicated last week
and struck another cart.
- [Happy] Stein-man!
- [groans]
Gilmore was arrested and charged with
vandalism and driving under the influence.
Prosecutors agreed to suspend
the golf-cart-related charges
on the condition that Gilmore
refrain from any physical violence
and attend a radical
alcohol treatment program.
Go Bruins!
He was also fired from his job
at Stop & Shop.
Truly, a sad end for a sports legend.
[man] Thanks for being with us today.
In 1996, you were arrested for
inciting injury to persons or property,
conspiracy to commit
vehicular manslaughter,
criminal menacing, and stealing a jacket.
[chuckles softly]
At trial, you were found not guilty
by reason of insanity
and remanded to this facility.
- That was 29 years ago.
- [exhales]
It feels like yesterday. [chuckles]
Twenty-nine years is a long time,
and so this board is inclined
to grant you your release.
If we were to do so, what then?
Well, I'd want to give back
to the community.
Especially the children who are,
of course, our future.
And animals, also,
who need to be snuggled,
and neutered with their permission,
of course.
What about Happy Gilmore?
Oh, I would stay far, far away.
Far, far away from Gilmore.
What if you ran into him,
say, on a golf course?
I'd wave or I could nod. That's also good.
And if he was wearing a gold jacket?
[Verne] Incredible!
- Happy Gilmore wins the gold jacket!
- No!
[breathing heavily]
I would fill a pillowcase with golf balls
and beat the piss out of him!
- I would tear the jacket off his back...
- [man] Guards.
...and shove it down his throat!
[man] Bring this animal back to his cell!
That is my jacket! My jacket!
Shooter's gold! All mine! It's my gold...
[door closes]
Lunch? Benihana?
- Hell yeah.
- [sighs]
- [indistinct chatter]
Excuse me. Is this where
the alcohol meetings are?
You're in the right place.
How are you feeling?
Mmm, a little shaky.
First five days are rough.
Just get through today and your body
will start turning the corner.
Thank you.
And this is all on the down low, right?
Happy freakin' Gilmore!
I can't believe
you be hitting the bottle too!
I guess Bessie
didn't get the down low memo.
Yeah, that's all right.
Where's the therapist?
He'll be here.
He likes to make an entrance.
Mr. Gilmore?
Holy shit.
[laughs] As I live and breathe.
It is wonderful to see you.
- [scoffs]
- How's Grandma?
Grandma? Passed away maybe 15 years ago.
Mmm. That's a shame.
I know you loved on her so much.
Yeah.
Is that when you began abusing alcohol?
No, no. That actually started up
after my wife got killed.
- Mm. It's always something, isn't it?
- Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Happy, why don't you come on up front?
We have a new member here.
Hi. I'm Happy and I'm an alcoholic.
Oh, we don't say alcoholic.
We're not scientists.
We're just people trying to get by.
We say "alkie". Keeps it light.
Uh... I'm Happy and I'm an alkie?
Say it loud and proud!
- Hi, I'm Happy and I'm an alkie!
- Ha-ha!
Celebrities. They just like us.
- Except they got a lot more cash.
- [all laugh]
Now, Charlotte,
last week you were concerned
about a musical festival
you were to attend.
How'd that work out?
- Fine. It was a concert.
- Mmm-hmm.
My friends were drinking
and offering me drinks,
but I didn't have any.
But I bet you wanted that liquor
something fierce, huh?
I mean, I was tempted, but...
I bet you would have kicked
your own mother in the face
just to get a sniff of that liquor,
wouldn't you?
Not really.
Charlotte, if we don't stop lying,
we don't stop drinking.
Why won't you stop lying?
Because I'm an alkie?
And how does a degenerate, low-life alkie
take the first step to recovery?
By washing your car?
Bingo! Three o'clock, Thursday?
I got the soap, you bring the rags
and bucket, we make it a party?
- I'm sorry, I have a question.
- Yeah?
What does the car-washing
have to do with the no-drinking?
You're thinking. You're thinking.
Mr. Gilmore's up in his head
when really he should be
listening to me
and keeping his mouth shut.
This is a radical
alcohol treatment program.
And the chief judge, my Uncle Dave,
he told me that I can do whatever I want
with everyone in this room.
Check out the name tag.
You're in my world now, Grandma.
You're in my world now.
Oh, my gosh.
[male voice]
Welcome to the future of golf.
The greatest game
just got a triple shot of adrenaline.
Experience the revolution of Maxi.
-Game over, regular golf.
- [laughs] Wow.
- Pretty great.
- [Lee] So good.
Yeah, it's something for sure. What is it?
- I mean, what are we seeing?
- What is it?
So, basically,
Maxi is a reimagining of golf.
It's golf for today.
Why is golf so boring and dumb?
Golf was invented 800 years ago,
something like that.
I thought about it and I was like,
"If society could change,
how come the rules of golf
have stayed the same?"
And that's why I created Maxi.
- That's deep.
- Yeah.
The NBA, the NFL, the NHL,
they offer the highest quality product.
- [softly] Wow.
- And so does Maxi.
You're saying Maxi
has the best golfers in the world?
Oh, my God.
- You doing okay, Frank?
- I think I'm going to die.
That's what's up, but listen, gang,
how are you going to get
these professional golfers
to play in this new league?
I've already got my golfers
and they're the best.
You think they're better than the pros?
I don't think, Stat. I know.
You should think about
talking to Happy Gilmore.
I don't know who that is.
- [Happy] Yeah, tell that to the lobsters.
- [John] Mmm.
Johnny, what are you doing
with those chicken wings?
They've been in the fridge
for three weeks now, bro.
I just put this sauce on them.
It gets rid of all the bacteria.
Hmm. I don't know about that,
but good luck.
When you've done that, the TV remote.
[sighs] Always wondered
why that didn't work.
What are you doing on that contuder?
I'm looking for a job.
There's a new Dairy Queen
around here. I think they're hiring.
You're not going to make
$330,000 at no Dairy Queen.
You know what you got to do.
I tried the golf.
The golf didn't work out. Cuckoo clock.
Grandma's cuckoo clock?
That's sacrilegious, Daddy.
- [Happy] Yeah, I know.
- [clock mimics cuckoo bird]
You can't give up
because of one bad round.
You had to at least
hit a couple decent shots.
I think I hit one out of 117.
Yeah, next time you'll hit two
and then three, and before you know it,
you're the best again.
I'm 58 years old, V.
Forget about being the best.
If you finish 30th
in the Tour Championship,
- you make 100 grand, brother.
- [Happy] How am I going to finish 30th?
I lost to three idiots
on a municipal course.
[John] You were hammered.
Maybe you need to practice, Dad,
like I do with dancing.
What else are you going to do, sober boy?
You can't drink.
Hand sanitizer.
Let Uncle John take care of that.
[gags] This is hand sanitizer.
[Happy] Gotcha. [laughs]
["Juke Box Hero" playing]
- Were you Happy Gilmore?
- Shh.
Um, do you want to try some clubs?
I do, yes.
Here, try the six iron.
A lot of pros like it.
Yep, uh, that'll do.
[vagrant mumbles indistinctly]
♪ He could picture the scene ♪
♪ Put his ear to the wall ♪
- [scoffs]
- No.
♪ He heard one guitar... ♪
To the right... Ooh!
Goddamn.
Hold my blanket.
Hold your blanket, all right.
All right, you want to load
on the back leg...
Uh-huh.
- And then...
- Yeah.
Okay, I'll... I'll handle it.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
- I don't know what happened.
- Just do your thing.
- Go!
- [men shouting indistinctly]
You got to be quicker.
What are you doing, Dad? Hey.
Sobriety is a journey, not a destination.
- [chimes]
- I believe in you, Happy!
♪ Someday he's going to make it
To the top ♪
♪ And be a juke box hero ♪
♪ Got stars in his eyes ♪
♪ He's a juke box hero... ♪
[laughs]
"What my teacher didn't understand,
what she couldn't understand,
"is that I only cheated on the test
because my mother had yelled at me
about the oatmeal cookies. Yet again..."
- [yells]
- [Bessie] Oh, there he goes.
[Hal] Nice even strokes.
Thank you, Charlotte.
Good. Finish the louvers,
then do the borders.
Yes, sir.
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Vienna Gilmore.
[Happy] Everyone else sucks
and you know it! Let's go, V!
♪ Like a trip through the past
To that day in the rain ♪
[man] Come on, Happy!
♪ And that one guitar
Made his whole life change ♪
♪ Now he needs to keep on rocking ♪
[all cheering]
♪ He just can't stop ♪
[all chanting] Happy! Happy!
♪ That boy has got to stay on top ♪
[crowd exclaiming, whooping]
Happy! Happy! Happy!
♪ He's got stars in his eyes ♪
- ♪ Juke box hero ♪
- ♪ Got stars in his eyes ♪
- Boot!
- [both cheer]
Come on, baby! You're back! Let's go.
Do you mind?
I'm sorry.
What the hell are you doing?
I'll take off. Have a good day.
Go back to your mobile home.
Got you a little something, Pop.
What? What is it?
"Thirty days sober! Congrats, Daddy!"
[all exclaiming]
- [Happy] You paint my house, brother.
- [all shouting]
[Gordy] Get him on the ground!
[all laughing, grunting triumphantly]
We'll put a little extra into this one.
[chanting] Happy! Happy! Happy!
[chanting stops]
I am so sorry. I did not mean to do that.
[all cheering]
♪ Juke box hero ♪
[yelling, groaning]
Damn you, Happy Gilmore!
I put a thermos of coffee in your
passenger seat, Dad, and a protein bar.
I love that. Thank you, Vivi.
You gonna bring back another gold jacket?
Don't be disappointed
if that doesn't happen.
Just looking to get in the top 30.
But that gets you enough money
to send Vienna to dance school.
You gotta do it.
One of us kids has to amount to something.
What are you talking about?
You're all something.
Something to me.
Get in here. Love you guys.
This is the first time you're gonna be
far away from us since Mom left.
We can FaceTime Dad every day.
It'll be okay.
- [Happy] Yeah, day or night. You hear me?
- [Bobby] Yeah.
And I'll be back Sunday to see you goons.
I promise you.
Hopefully with one of them big checks.
Hell yeah, Dad. Let's go.
Make sure John Daly
doesn't sleep in my bed.
If he does, no M&M's. Okay?
- Got it.
Arnold.
Jack-o.
Tiger.
SpongeBob?
What is that?
What's with the beaver teeth?
[Doug] The truth can hurt sometimes.
- Oh, my goodness. Dougie boy!
- Happy! [chuckles]
I missed you, bro.
How's everything been going?
Oh, it gets harder every year, Happy.
How's it getting harder? I'm not around.
Yeah, honestly, the Maxi Golf League.
The Maxi... I saw a commercial for that.
It looked stupid.
- Well, supposedly, it is faster-paced...
- Yeah, yeah.
...and our biggest sponsors
are suddenly slow to call me back.
I got a bad feeling about this.
We got the greatest golfers in the world.
That's what people want to see, the best.
Manatee says his guys are better.
There's only one way to find out.
Challenge him.
People would love to watch that.
Wow! Virginia really rubbed off on you.
We had five kids together.
She rubbed off on me all the time,
and I just laid there
like a sack of potatoes.
[chuckles] As charming as ever.
Hey, just get inside.
The guys are excited to see you.
Would you at least get Invisalign
for that thing? Thank you.
Hey, Happy, you gonna finish off
that blueberry jubilee?
Oh, God. Freddy's still snaking
everybody's dessert? Okay, you got it.
Thank you. Cheers.
I'm so happy to be with you.
Look forward to getting out there.
You gonna play tomorrow?
Why, you guys aren't playing?
Happy, these kids are 20, 30 years old.
We're old and stiff.
We're old, but we're still cool.
You guys taking aspirin
before you get out there?
I'm popping them like Tic Tacs.
I grind them in my applesauce.
I used to be able to play 72 holes
without breaking a sweat.
Now it takes me ten minutes
to get out of this chair.
- [all chuckle]
- Yes?
Do you mind grabbing me
a half iced tea and half lemonade?
Arnold Palmer.
No, Jack Nicklaus,
but I do get that a lot.
Fantastic. Be back in a jiff.
Happy, what gives with the comeback
attempt after all these years?
Well, I'm out of cash.
My daughter has an opportunity
to go to this ballet school in Paris, so...
Happy, I've known you for 30 years.
You're like a son to me.
How much you need?
300 grand.
Good luck tomorrow. Hit 'em straight.
- Excuse me, pal?
- Yes, sir?
I asked for a Tanqueray and tonic,
but they gave me Bombay instead.
I'm the busboy, sir.
Sorry. I will get you a server right now.
Uh, do you want some bread?
No, just the right booze, thanks.
Okay.
I think I rattled him.
Hey, Happy, whatever happened to that guy,
uh, Shooter McGavin?
I believe he's still
in an institution, Jack.
Wasn't he friends with O.J.?
Well, they used to vacation together.
I don't know if they were friends, but...
- [thunder rumbling]
- [laughing]
This guy's losing it.
[laughs wickedly]
[door opens]
What are you doing here? It's quiet time.
You suddenly got some
very powerful friends, McGavin.
This is a court order
for your immediate release.
Excuse me?
Gentleman would like new gin and tonic.
He said Bombay, no Tanqueray.
You told Spiethy that was on me, man?
No, no.
You threw me under the bus.
So you could be the hero?
[Oscar] No. I... No.
[Travis] You stabbed me in my back.
That's what time it is?
He just, he just said...
I can't work like this, man.
Watching my six all day, every day.
I just wanted to help. I offered bread.
You mess around, you find out.
You're fired.
Fired?
- [barks]
- [yelps]
Hey, pal. Yo. You think
you were a little harsh on the dude?
Sorry you had to hear that, Mr. Gilmore.
You don't know the backstory.
Mr. Couples? More blueberry jubilee?
Nah, I'm okay. Maybe one more.
Yeah. Back in two.
[thunder rumbling]
Yackety-yack, don't come back.
Whoo!
Ah! [laughs]
[breathes deeply, laughs]
[horn honking]
Shooter McGavin. I'm such a massive fan.
[glass clinking]
Gentlemen, thank you for being here
at the Tour Champions Dinner.
That's what she said.
I'm not sure that made sense, X.
Every time our sport has overcome
a challenge, we have come out stronger.
Today's challenge is the Maxi Golf League,
who allege that they are
going to make golf more watchable.
That's what she said.
- Great joke, Mr. Schauffele.
- Thanks, buddy.
I just got off the phone
with the president
of this new league, Frank Manatee,
and I challenged him to a competition.
Frank accepted that challenge
and then farted into the phone.
He did what?
What's the competition?
Our five best players
versus his five best.
Make it our five worst. It doesn't matter.
We're gonna smoke them anyway!
[all cheering]
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
Now, I know that you all want the honor
of kicking their ass.
- [all] Yeah!
- So how about this?
Top five finishers this weekend
represent us in the challenge.
All right. Let's go.
[mouthing] That's what she said.
Gentlemen, by showing
the world our dominance,
we will eliminate this league
before it even officially launches.
- [player] Let's go!
- [all cheering]
And now you've got something else
to play for, Happy.
Yeah! Yeah!
- [both groan]
- Gosh. I think there's a fork in my ass.
Now that's what she said.
- Yeah!
- [all cheering]
- [whoops]
- [both whoop]
[Verne] The sun is shining.
The greens are shimmering.
What a day to play some golf.
Welcome to the big one,
the U.S. Bank Tour Championship.
I'm Verne Lundquist.
Here, as always, with Jack Beard.
And the golfer everyone is talking about,
Happy Gilmore.
- Looks handsome.
- Yeah.
[Verne] Gilmore returns
after a ten-year absence.
[woman] Some of the guys
set your locker up.
Bengay, Tums. Preparation H, yeah.
MiraLAX, always good.
And, uh, diapers. Now that's pushing it.
I know you never made it
to the Bruins, Happy,
but maybe you'll make
this five-man wrecking crew.
Oh, I doubt that, Tony. I'm actually
just worried about making the cut.
Mr. Gilmore, Sergio told me
you forgot to bring a caddie
to your first tournament. Is that true?
[laughs] He said that? No.
Well, yeah, but still,
I didn't know the rules back then.
That's insane.
Yeah, that was silly.
Can't believe I would do that.
[choking]
Hey, brother. Good to see you, man.
So here's what happened.
My regular caddie moved to Switzerland
for tax purposes,
so I'm kind of like, I got nowhere to go.
What do you say,
you and me for old times' sake?
That's nice, Mr. Gilmore,
but I, unfortunately,
I can't caddie for you today.
You're not still mad about
the whole choking you thing, are you?
No, it's not that.
It's actually, I don't caddie anymore.
I, uh... I play now.
We're actually playing together today.
I didn't know that, Blondie.
All right, well, I'll see you out there.
I'll see ya.
Blondie. [chuckles]
My name's Will, and I'm still mad at you
for choking me out, you son of a bitch.
[Verne] We're minutes away from the start,
and Happy Gilmore is apparently
breaking in yet another new caddie.
Uh, it's a club. Yeah.
Club. Oh, like the club sandwich.
Not the club sandwich. Okay.
[Verne] Let's check in
with our own Gary Potter,
who's with number one-ranked
Scottie Scheffler.
Thanks, Verne.
Scottie, you have been on quite a tear.
My God.
You're seeing the ball and the hole,
and the position of the ball
and the hole... all good things.
Is there a question in there, Gary?
Scottie, if you're the best,
does that make everyone else the worst?
I'm just gonna go warm up.
Always great catching up with Scottie.
Back to you, Verne.
Thanks, Gary.
The threesome of Justin Thomas,
Will Zalatoris,
and Happy Gilmore is about to tee off.
- Ooh.
- [crowd cheering, applauding]
Nice. Nice bang, JT.
Pressure's on with Happy watching.
My family loves you.
I'm actually rooting for you.
I gotta stop.
No. Keep it coming.
I need all the love I can get.
Gotcha.
- Now on the tee, Zalatoris, Will.
- [chuckles]
- That's your name?
"That's your name?" What an idiot.
I'm a little intimidated.
All these guys hit it big now, you know?
Do you need a water refill?
Any breadsticks?
No. Maybe I'll go to my happy place.
Okay. I will be here.
[crowd cheering]
It's not working.
I don't drink beer anymore.
Good.
Now on the tee, Gilmore, Happy.
[man] Welcome back, Happy!
[Verne] Golf fans around the world
are excited to see Happy Gilmore again,
but at 58 years old,
I'm not sure even Gilmore thinks
he can compete with today's best.
[man] Hey, Happy!
I guess I need to update my happy place
to something a little more
age appropriate.
Whoa! [laughing]
[yelping]
[bell ringing]
You can do it! [laughs]
Yeah.
- [ball whizzing]
- [crowd murmuring]
[crowd cheering]
Okay.
- Thank you, Happy!
- [all cheering]
- Let's go!
Never did that before. Thank you, man.
Okay, well, let's get--
All right, we're going to go.
- But you bring those. Those always come.
- Oh.
All right? That's it, that's it.
I'm sorry.
No, no. They got a strap
if you want to use the strap.
["She Sells Sanctuary" playing]
[crowd cheering]
A snake! Get it off me, god damn it!
Get the snake!
[Happy] Come on. Come on. Come on.
- [cheering]
- Goal! Yeah, baby!
- Come on, Happy!
- [indistinct chatter]
Man, I don't drink.
How about some coffee?
That I can do! Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go.
[all chanting] Chug, chug, chug!
[cheering]
Yeah!
Yeah! Let's go! Yeah!
[yelling]
Holy shit!
[crowd cheering]
[woman] Still the man, Happy!
- [phone rings]
- It's my kids. Sorry, everyone.
- Good to see you, boy!
- There they are.
Daddy's on the tee...
Wanna see Daddy drive the ball?
Please, dear. Thank you.
All right, boys. This is for you.
Whoa!
Oh! Daddy got a hold of that one.
What are you doing?
Gordy! You got to see a doctor about that!
Happy! Happy! Happy!
[Verne] Entering day two
and feeding off the fans' support,
Happy Gilmore has jumped into the top ten.
Oscar. Where were you? Who's this?
Oh, he's Esteban, my caddie.
- Okay.
- Steven.
Steven, nice to meet...
No. You don't get a caddie.
Caddies don't get caddies. I'm sorry.
No? Can he play?
What do you mean... He's not...
This is the pro tournament.
I'm sorry. He's gotta go.
[conversing in Spanish]
[in English] Happy Gilmore! Okay, got it.
[speaks Spanish] Okay.
[Happy in English] All right. Ciao. Adiós.
He took his hat.
All right, go! [laughs]
Okay, we got to play, man.
Let me have the driver.
Oh, damn it. [sighs, growls]
[caddie choking] Wait! Please!
Now he gets it.
[crowd exclaiming, cheering]
- Happy! Happy!
- That was the shot.
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
[Verne] And heading into Saturday,
two shots back.
The comeback kid, Happy Gilmore.
- [man] Good shot, Happy!
- [crowd cheering]
[crowd cheering]
[men] Happy! Rules!
- [gagging]
- [crowd chanting] Happy! Happy!
Guys, what are you doing?
I'm trying to watch your dad play golf!
- Guys, we can't hear!
- Come on, guys.
[Verne] No one could have expected this.
Happy Gilmore.
From off the couch to the top
of the leaderboard.
And what was supposed to be
a nostalgic footnote
has turned into one of the best
three rounds anyone has ever seen.
The thing is,
if I go for this and miss the cup,
it's going to roll
right off the green, so... yeah.
- Okay, I see.
- Yeah.
What's a green?
Green? Know what?
Don't worry about that right now.
What I'm looking for
is some positive energy, you know?
Can I help?
Actually, you can.
Remember the happy place I went to?
- Yes.
- You go to yours.
Okay, I'll try.
[breathes deeply]
What's up, man?
What do you got there? Honey?
What is this? What is this?
Is this about the job? Come on--
Let's-- [giggling] That's-- Come on, man.
- Oh, no. Not a bear. Not a bear.
- [sniffing]
- Goddamn you, busboy!
- [growls]
[screams]
[mimics growling]
- I'm happy now. Hit the ball.
- Yeah.
Yes.
You were thinking about
a bear eating that waiter, weren't you?
Yes.
- I thought so. Was there honey involved?
- Un poquito.
[in English] I love it.
[man] Come on, Happy.
- [woman] Come on, Happy.
- [crowd murmuring]
[Verne] Oh, no.
I don't see that one stopping.
Wait a minute.
- Zalatoris' ball marker to the rescue!
- [cheering]
Yeah, Blondie! [laughs]
And the fairy tale continues.
Happy Gilmore has somehow
turned back the hands of time.
- No. Not again.
- Come here. Come on!
We gotta do it!
- [crowd] Oh!
- [groaning]
- I love it! Yeah, Oscar! Whoo!
Less than two months
after hitting rock bottom
in a drunken golf cart crash,
Happy Gilmore is 18 holes away
from a seventh gold jacket.
The only possible conclusion is that
Happy Gilmore has reached an agreement
of some kind
with Satan, a.k.a. the Devil!
[man] All right. Let's go! Happy!
- Good job, Mr. Gilmore.
- What's up?
In the zone today. Man.
We were putting. We were doing okay.
A little luck involved.
Hey, Mr. Gilmore. Billy Jenkins.
- Hey, nice to meet you, Bobby.
- Billy.
Billy was on fire today.
I was like, where did that come from?
Had the best round of my life.
I'm in second place.
You and me play tomorrow.
You're kidding. Look forward to that.
I've never been in the hunt.
It's a dream come true.
You're going to love it.
You get in the top five,
you get to play against those buffoons
from the new league.
What's up with that tool
starting that league?
The guy came to see me to talk about it.
He had the worst breath
I've ever smelled in my life.
Like somebody died in his mouth
or a donkey took a shit there
or something...
It was not good.
Anyways, I got to get to a meeting.
Love you, Bubba. David, good to see you.
It's Billy.
[clears throat] So, in summary, I am no
longer allowed to purchase magic markers
in the state of Connecticut.
I am Nate,
and I am one day sober. [chuckles]
- Nate, you're an example to us all.
- [laughs]
What?
Before we finish,
I'd like to say a few words
about the remarkable achievement
of our brother, Happy.
We've been watching you play, Mr. Gilmore.
So inspiring.
Yeah! Happy Gilmore, making Black people
like golf again. [chuckles]
[Hal] That's right, Bessie.
I just hope Happy's able to
continue to play as well tomorrow.
Tomorrow being of course... Oh...
Mother's Day.
[Verne] Welcome to the final round
of the Tour Championship.
Here come your current leaders.
Journeyman Billy Jenkins,
getting his first taste of success
after an undistinguished career.
The only man in his way,
a golf magician
named Happy Octavius Gilmore.
Octavius is his middle name?
Nah, but it sounds cool, doesn't it?
Wait a minute.
Can't wear shorts, Mr. Jenkins.
It's a two-stroke penalty.
That's okay.
I don't want to be hot today.
Makes my balls itchy.
[Verne] Was that confidence
or just pure stupidity?
[crowd exclaiming, applauding]
[announcer] Now on the tee,
Gilmore, Happy.
[Happy] Nice shot, young man.
[Verne] Happy Gilmore will try to defend
his eight-shot lead
on this glorious Mother's Day.
Gilmore was aiming right for some reason,
and that's where it went.
A lot of holes left to play.
[softly] Yeah.
It's okay. [speaks Spanish]
- [humming]
- [knock on door]
- Mr. McGavin.
- [chuckles]
How'd you sleep?
This place... is amazing.
The pillows, the steam shower,
the free porn,
and these fluffy pancakes. Oh, my God.
What do you say you and I go on a tour
- and I show you what we're all about?
- Mmm...
I'll make sure there's a fresh stack
waiting for you when we get back.
All right.
Slippers on?
And why don't you throw on
some underpants, too?
[man 1] It's all right, Happy.
[man 2] Hey, Happy. Remember me?
My dad used to be your boss
when you worked in construction.
I'm truly proud of you.
Hey, thanks a lot, Mr. Larson.
Drago Larson. Little Drago Larson?
Hell yeah! My God!
I always felt bad about what I did
to Daddy and the whole nail thing.
Actually, after he got it removed,
he kind of missed it,
so he had it put back.
Oh, okay.
He passed away a few years ago.
I'm so sorry. What happened?
He rolled over in his sleep.
Oh, yeah.
At least I still have Mom.
Every boy needs his mom.
- Yeah.
- Happy have five kids, Mom.
Oh, tell your wife Happy Mother's Day.
His wife passed away.
Oh, I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
Why didn't you tell me, Jerko?
Mommy, don't hit me. Mommy, don't hit me.
Which club do you prefer, sir?
[man 3] Let's go, Gilmore!
- Give me... Let me have a wedge.
- [crowd murmuring]
[man 4] Let's go, Happy.
- Every boy needs a mom.
- But we don't have one.
[man 4] You got it, Happy.
- You can make it.
- You got this.
[man 4] Do it. Come on.
- [thuds]
- [crowd murmuring, exclaiming] Oh!
I gotta go to the bathroom.
[Frank] You came at a very special moment.
Change is in the air.
What change is that?
Golf. New and improved.
Gilmore must love all this.
I wouldn't know.
Happy Gilmore's a broken man.
A broken man?
Yeah, ever since the loss of his wife.
Wait, Virginia Venit?
Is that what her name was?
Oh, man.
[exhales heavily]
[automated voice] Fart recognized.
All right, come on in.
[Verne] Our current leader, Happy Gilmore,
has been in the restroom
for an unusually long time.
[melancholy music plays]
Let's play some golf.
[Verne] Billy Jenkins is playing
an inspired round.
Meanwhile, Happy Gilmore is struggling
to keep it in the fairway.
- [crowd exclaiming]
- [whines]
[Happy] Cart path.
Wanna sip of my 3-wood?
- No, gracias.
- Okay.
You scratch it, I hurt you.
[gasps, laughs]
Thank you, Jesus!
[Gary] Plenty golf to be played.
Happy, what does Mother's Day mean to you?
Can you suck my white ass, Gary?
Just suck the entire thing?
Psycho.
[crowd exclaim] Oh.
[Verne] And it has all fallen apart
for Happy Gilmore...
Happy's... wasted!
...who is staggering,
literally, to the finish.
[beeps, unlocks]
What I'm about to show you
is the foundation of Maxi Golf.
[Shooter] An X-ray from 1957.
Who's Ben Daggett?
He's the only guy who could hit it farther
than Happy Octavius Gilmore.
[Shooter] How come I never heard of him?
[Frank] Well, he was a degenerate.
Couldn't putt for shit.
Just drove around the country
in the 1950s,
dominating long drive contests.
They say he could
carry the ball 500 yards.
One day, one of the mobsters
who he owed some money to
took a golf shoe
and shoved it right up Ben's ass.
And that's where this X-ray was taken.
Do you see anything unusual here?
Well, there appears to be a shoe
up his rectal region.
That's true. But see that?
That's the iliolumbar ligament.
Why is it in two pieces?
Let me guess. Shoe up the ass?
- No.
- No?
This happened much earlier in his life.
Turns out Daggett severed it
in a childhood go-kart accident.
The separation of the ligament
from when he was a kid
increased Daggett's range of motion
in his hips,
dramatically improving
the amount of torque
and club speed that he could generate.
That's why he could hit it so far.
Because of the shoe.
Will you stop with the shoe?
We're done with the shoe.
It was a go-kart accident
that severed the ligament
and turned him into
a long-ball-hitting freak.
And all those golfers outside?
We snipped
their iliolumbar ligaments, too.
That's cheating.
Who would agree to a surgery like that?
[Frank] Journeymen...
who were good enough for the pros
but could never figure out
how to beat the legends.
[crowd exclaiming]
[crowd applauding]
It's all in the hips, Grandpa.
It's all in the hips.
Shooter, I want you to be the captain
of the Maxi team.
Hmm.
- Thank you so much.
- Absolutely, Mr. Manatee.
Pancakes next time.
And I haven't even showed you
the best part yet.
18 holes? Boring.
We do seven holes.
Slow play? [scoffs] We got shot clocks.
My God, this is obscene.
It's a lot to take in. I get it.
I will never have anything
to do with this...
This abomination.
You know, Shooter, it wasn't very easy
to get you released.
But it'd be pretty damn easy
to get you recommitted.
Yeah?
[gasps] Damn, that's hot.
- I was told you liked it hot.
- Do you?
- [yells]
- [yelps, screams]
[laughing]
- [shattering]
- [screaming]
[continues screaming]
My eye! [screaming]
Yesterday, Happy Gilmore had
the entire sports world rooting for him,
and then he took all that good will
and basically set it on fire.
-Go to your happy place!
- [Happy] No!
[Pat] He also lost out on playing
against the Maxi League
as he finds himself
with a sixth-place finish.
And so it is Jenkins
who will lead the five-man team
against the upstart Maxi League,
or... so we thought.
Sorry to pee in your punch bowl, folks,
but I am actually a proud member
of the Maxi Golf League.
Bye-bye, regular golf. Bye-bye.
That's right. Billy's part of a new league
where we hit longer,
look cooler, and party harder.
And the best part is,
our guys are "Maxi Good."
- Give me the jacket.
- [coughs]
[Stephen] My sources
in the DA's office say
Gilmore's actions
violated a plea agreement,
relating to his drunken golf cart crash
earlier this year,
and that he only avoided arrests
due to an ally causing a distraction.
[Drago groaning]
Hey, Drago,
you forgot your underpants, Jerko!
Gilmore is now facing six years
in state prison,
but I hope the authorities
will deliver justice to golf fans
by sentencing him to the electric chair,
which at this point, he richly deserves.
[Shooter] Oh, Virginia,
I'm sorry you're no longer with us.
You were a woman
working in a man's league.
I bet that wasn't easy. Huh?
Yeah. I guess I should also apologize
for asking you to get me a Pepsi.
[Happy] Diet.
Gilmore.
Shooter McGavin.
Last time I saw you, you were running away
in slow motion with my gold jacket.
That was my jacket!
Take it. I've got five others.
[exhales in frustration]
God! You would never
have won them if I wasn't--
What? In the loony bin?
You stole my life from me.
Now, why would I want
to steal the life of somebody
who eats pieces of shit...
- Oh, you...
- ...for breakfast?
[chuckles, yells]
- [both groaning]
- [grunts]
Game over, bitch. [choking]
- Come on.
- Okay.
- Let's go.
- We're gonna fist fight?
- Want this?
- Yeah.
You sure you want that? Come on.
[both grunting]
Come here, now.
[pants] That was for you, Grandma.
I am so sorry I lost the house again.
- Truly.
- Hi, Grandma.
- Don't you ever talk to my grandma!
- [yells]
[grunts] Come on.
- [yells] Jackass!
- [groans]
[both panting]
That was round one.
We are done, son.
You can tell everybody you won.
Should I put my hair in a bun
just for fun?
And play one-on-one with Attila the Hun?
- Oh, boy. That was good. Round two.
- [groans]
Okay. We're even.
Come on. You love this.
- Get up. Absolutely.
- Thanks, man.
Okay. Hey.
Are your hip ligaments cut in half?
I don't think so.
Anyone ever stick a shoe up your ass?
Not that I can recollect.
You realize these are strange questions?
Apparently, if a certain hip ligament
is not attached,
you can hit the ball farther.
Oh. No. I always powered my drives
the old-fashioned way. With rage.
Yeah.
You want to get out of these pajamas?
I live around here.
Yeah, thanks.
Mister! Mister! Get me outta here!
[yelps]
They issued a warrant
for your arrest, Dad.
[Wayne] Yeah, hide in the basement.
I should just turn myself in.
Get it over with.
- We'll ask the lawyer when he gets here.
- You hired a lawyer?
Okay. How do I look?
[Bobby] You look like my frickin' dad.
[chuckles] Yeah.
At least I'm not wearing
that ridiculous Bruins jersey.
Uh-oh.
[all shouting indistinctly]
Okay.
- [knock on door]
- [shouting stops]
Okay, get the door.
Mr. Gilmore. Mr. McGavin. John Daly.
- Nice to see you again.
- [snores]
You're the lawyer?
I thought you were the IRS guy.
I was, but I got tired
of everybody hating me
and occasionally being thrown
through a glass door.
You hate me, don't you?
[grunting]
- Right.
- So, I went to law school.
You didn't want to be hated anymore,
so you became a lawyer?
[all laughing]
- [Happy] That's funny.
- Lawyers are snobs.
- Pieces of shit.
Let's sit. Lots to talk about.
Let me just have a little shower...
This girl's got some body on her.
Hey, we do not objectify women anymore.
- [squirt]
- What?
Okay, great. Uh, looks like the DA
has withdrawn the arrest warrant.
What?
Even though you appeared to some onlookers
to be inebriated at the tournament,
you weren't administered an alcohol test.
- And... I have better news.
- [Happy] Yes?
You came in sixth at that tournament.
That's right. I forgot about that.
How much did I win?
Uh, $496,000.
- Oh, my God!
- No way!
- No! What?
- Holy shit!
[Happy] Baby! Yay!
Now you're really gonna hate me.
The tour is fining you
$500,000 for bad behavior.
So he lost $37,000?
No. It's $33,000, Dad.
It's $4,000, you buffoons.
How is that good news?
Well, you came in sixth,
but the winner, Billy Jenkins,
opted out of the tour team
because he's playing for the bad guys.
So you made the team.
- Dad, that's great!
- Whoa! Okay, Pop.
They don't want me. I'm a disgrace.
A freaking embarrassment.
Let's go outside, Dad, for a second.
Next.
Well, Shooter,
due to Mr. Manatee's sworn statement,
you are now technically an escapee
from a mental institution.
[laughs] Welcome to the club.
[squirts]
Dad, it doesn't matter
if you play for that team or not.
You have to stop drinking.
I did. It's just--
Just nothing.
You gotta find peace somehow.
There's no peace. I...
The reason I joined that tour again
was to get you the future you deserve,
and I lost $4,000.
You think if you made that money
I could leave you like this?
It's not your job to take care of me.
I told you.
- Of course it is. We're family.
- You're stuck with us.
Yeah, come on, Dad.
I don't want you to be stuck with me.
You didn't do nothing wrong. It's me.
I think this person could help.
Hey, you gotta put
a little mustard on that ball
so it doesn't get stuck
where the pirate hide his, uh, uh...
booty and shit.
The hold?
Yeah, the hold. Get at it, kiddies.
- Thank you!
- Are you Slim Peterson?
That's what they call me.
Your dad Chubbs was my teacher.
My name's Happy Gilmore--
I know who you are.
Hey, you gotta hit it under the octopus
and bank it off one of his leg things.
The tentacles?
Yeah, testicles. Now, what was you saying?
[Happy] I need to talk to you
for a few minutes.
Damn, mosquitoes. They everywhere.
- What...
- Look at them.
Alligator?
No, vending machine.
I didn't have enough change.
Had to reach up there to get
my Famous Amos chocolate chip cookies.
Man, looking at you just reminded me
of what I did to you.
What'd you do to me?
What I did to my own kids. Stole a parent.
Man, you gotta forgive yourself for that.
[Happy] Don't want to.
I didn't want to forgive you either,
because it was easier to hate you
than to deal with the fact
that my daddy wasn't coming back.
It's kind of like I was using hate
to keep him alive.
But once I forgave you,
I became myself again.
And that's who I knew
my daddy wanted me to be.
[sighs] You loved your wife.
You loved my dad.
And they loved you, period.
You know what else they loved? Golf.
Oh, my God, yeah.
I talked to your little girl,
and she said you got a chance
to save the whole sport
by playing against some clown league?
Yeah, well, why don't you go kick
some bozo ass then?
Let's do it for them.
I am so sorry.
Boy, why you had to squeeze it like that?
I will throw these out. I can...
Give them here. I got some Gorilla Glue.
Yeah, love you, buddy.
Yeah, man, thank you for stopping by.
You know, we could use some help.
Oh, about time somebody
recognized my genius. Say less.
Okay, okay.
Where do you think you're going, Slim?
I'm going to help save golf, Charley.
If you leave now, you ain't ever
coming back, you big pork chop.
Damn straight I ain't never coming back,
you fine-ass English hillbilly.
[Doug] Welcome, gentlemen.
You are the five golfers
who will represent our tour
in the grudge match
against the Maxi League.
I don't have to tell you
how important it is that we beat them.
And here to talk about how we're going to
accomplish that is Shooter McGavin.
Thank you, Doug. I'll take it from here.
I want to talk to you about pressure.
Now, as the most successful golfer
of the '90s,
I've faced my share, believe me,
but nothing like my 30 years in the can.
And if I let my guard down there
for a nanosecond...
- Stab!
- [gasps]
I got a shiv in my guts.
Anyway, I hear you guys
all have ice water in your veins.
Well, I reviewed the footage
and I ain't seeing it.
- Man, what's happening right now?
- Uh...
Bryson DeChambeau.
2022 Portland Open. Eighth hole.
You got a two-stroke lead.
You got an opportunity
to pull way ahead and... [clicks tongue]
- [crowd] Aw!
- What?
Huh?
Oops.
Come on. We all miss a putt
every now and then.
Scottie Scheffler.
Oh, boy.
2019 Cadillac Invitational.
Third hole. You're tied.
Top of the leaderboard.
It's Sunday. Pressure's on. And you...
[crowd exclaim in disappointment]
Hmm. Into the woods.
The woods, Scottie? Are you afraid to win?
- What about you?
- What?
Yeah. 1996 Tour Championship. Final round.
Don't do it, boys.
No. This isn't relevant.
Four-stroke lead on the back nine?
The guy who beat you
got hit by a Volkswagen.
- Jackass!
All right! Maybe I haven't handled
the pressure perfectly myself,
but I have seen the surgically modified
freaks that you're playing.
I have seen the monstrosity
they're making you play on.
And if you can't take the heat,
golf, as we know it, it's finished!
So let's do this!
Come on. Let's put them in.
All right. On three.
- One, two, three... Shooter!
- [players] Golf!
Time to prepare for a moving target.
The cups are gonna be moving?
Damn it, Rory.
Nothing's off-limits for these commies.
- Now, Oscar's cousin...
- Esteban.
Esteban is fast. And elusive, I'm told.
He's gonna start at the red flag.
If he makes it to the blue flag,
we haven't done our jobs.
He's cool with us hitting him?
Yeah. He's been paid.
- [shouts in Spanish]
- [in English] What did he say?
You're never gonna hit him.
Oh, yeah? How come?
I'm shifty!
Okay, he's shifty. He is. I've seen it.
[blows whistle]
♪ Get your biscuits in the kitchen ♪
♪ I'm a sous chef on a mission ♪
♪ Baby, wiggle it, it's vicious ♪
♪ We about to break the dishes ♪
♪ Got the pepper with the sodium ♪
♪ We cookin' with petroleum
Come step up to the podium ♪
It's too easy!
♪ And cut up this linoleum ♪
[laughs, groans]
Yeah!
You got me! [laughs]
[in Spanish] Come on, cousin.
You're almost there.
[grunting]
[giggling]
- [groans]
- [whistle blows]
Okay, stop! We got him. We got him.
[yelps]
I said stop! Who did that?
[Happy] Oscar. You sicko.
- So I got a hockey question for you.
- Uh-huh.
I notice when the players fight,
one of the guys is always pulling
the jersey over the head of the other guy
- before he starts pounding on him.
- Right.
- Yeah.
- Is that hard?
- No, it's easy. You want me to show you?
- Yes, please.
Brother. Can I borrow you for a second?
Basically all you do
is pull the shirt over.
This traps the arms. You know?
- Yeah.
- Knockout. Money.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Okay. How much?
Fifty.
Uh, I'll give you a hundred.
Here we go. You know what I mean?
Yeah. That was nice.
- Okay. Money.
- Okay. You got it, Scottie. I'm broke.
- Thank you.
- There you go. Okay.
Great job, today, by the way.
- Excellent. Yeah, it's fun.
- Yeah. That was easy.
I love my job.
Mini-golf-style putting is about
two things, angles and obstacles.
If you can read the angles,
you can avoid the obstacles.
Let's putt
so we can figure those angles out.
Yes! Scheffler!
Yeah, you're right.
One more day before we face these chumps.
This is how I used to toughen up.
[groans]
[yelping]
[grunts]
[Happy] Oh, my God, Rory! [laughs]
Okay, Oscar, let's see your stuff.
[grunts softly]
[exhales]
[grunts]
♪ Sittin' down is stupid
Now let me see you move it ♪
- [groaning]
- Oh! Do you want breadsticks?
[Billy] A batting cage to toughen up?
I love how much we're in your head.
Oh, I think we're in your head, Brendan.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be snooping around
and following us.
My name is Billy.
Hey, settle down, Barry,
and get off the electric Royce.
No leaning.
Look, Happy, I don't want to
have to humiliate you tomorrow.
You're in the DNA of my league.
The way you rebelled
against the traditions
and fussiness of golf, it was beautiful.
So I'm gonna offer you one last chance
to be a part of it, okay?
[Happy] Hell no.
And you look like Freddy Krueger
worked at Starbucks. Change it.
I'll give you 10% of the company.
I can't believe I'm the one
sticking up for tradition, but...
My wife liked the way
golf was played, as is.
And she was pretty much
right about everything.
So sorry, boys, but tomorrow,
your dumb league is done.
No, tomorrow, I'm gonna finish
the revolution you started.
I heard what you said
about my breath to Bubba Watson.
I have gingivitis. It's hereditary, okay?
And I got it from my great-grandfather.
So I'm so sorry.
I'm literally smelling it from here.
And the wind is blowing that way.
Something has to change in your life.
I'm telling you.
[blaring]
[blaring stops]
[Happy] Okay.
Come here. Bring it in.
I just wanted to say thank you guys
for always getting me back on track.
- I love you.
- [Vienna] Love you.
This ain't about Vivi going to
dance school. It's about saving golf?
Maybe we can do both,
but we will figure that out, I promise.
Because we're Gilmores,
and we don't know how to stop.
[Gordy] Hell yeah, Pop, let's go!
And don't forget to feed John Daly
three times a day.
- Okay.
- Got it.
- Love you guys.
- [Gordy] You heard him.
Let's do this for Mom.
- [Bobby] For Mom!
- [Wayne] For Mommy.
- You got this.
- That's right.
That's right. She deserves it.
- [Bobby] Go get 'em, Dad.
- [engine splutters]
[Gordy] Pop...
- All right.
- [Terry] Yeah!
- [Wayne] What's going on?
- Let's go.
- Go Dad, you got this.
- Go Daddy!
- What's going on?
- [Happy] Stupid.
- Damn it.
- Are you kidding me?
[all grunting, clamoring]
What are you doing?
[Terry] What's with this guy?
What you doing hitting my dad's car?
This is a family affair, bro!
- [indistinct shouting]
- [Happy] Take him down, boys! Let's go!
- [Bobby] Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- What's he doing?
Get him!
Chase him! That's right!
- [Gordy] Where you going?
- [Bobby] Get him!
What the hell is happening?
[Verne] Welcome to an event
unique in the annals of sport.
A one-time showdown
between golf's greatest players
and the wild upstarts
who seek to supplant them.
Let's get it on.
Welcome to the Maxi Tour Challenge.
I'm Verne Lundquist,
along with my partner, Jack Beard,
and my new partner, DJ Omar Gosh.
Truly bitching to be here, Verne.
[rock music playing]
[Frank] Ladies and gentlemen
of planet Earth!
Are you prepared to have your minds blown?
[crowd cheering]
I'm tippy-toeing.
I said I'm tip-- Thank you.
I said are you guys ready to see some golf
so exciting your heads will explode?
Whoo!
[Frank] Here are the Maxi Golfers!
- [crowd cheering]
- [woman] Go Harley!
[Frank] We've got Harley...
Flex!
Screech!
8 Ball!
And Tour Champion Billy Jenkins!
["Eye Of The Tiger" playing]
And now let's welcome their opponents,
the Basic Vanilla Regular Golfers.
- Boo!
- [crowd booing]
["Goodbye to You" playing]
♪ Goodbye to you ♪
Holy shit! Is that Shooter McGavin?
[Frank] Look who decided to show.
You never finished your pancakes,
by the way.
You want coffee in your other eye?
Ha! Get a furlough
from the Funny Farm, Shitter?
- Laugh it up Blue Balls.
- It's 8 Ball!
Your name's Davis Miller.
You're my brother's college roommate.
It's 8 Ball now!
Tell him I said what's up.
You guys get these clothes
from the Lost and Found at Comic-Con?
Did you get these melons
from your mommy? Yeah?
Don't twist my boy's titties!
Those are mine!
- Hey, I'll twist your head off, slap-nuts!
- [shouting, clamoring]
Break it up! All right, knock it off!
Golfers, we have a seven-hole course.
First up, Mr. Scheffler
going up against Mr. Harley.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's play some Maxi Golf!
[crowd cheering]
- [John] Let's drink up! Come on, let's go!
- Yeah! All right! Whoo!
- Here.
- No, I'm good.
- You got your own.
- Mmm.
- I want to try that.
- Mmm-mmm.
[Verne] And so it begins, hole number one.
Best of five matches,
so we only gotta win three of them today.
I say we sweep these goofy bitches.
- That's a good idea.
- [Bryson] Yeah.
The fairway's a forest?
I don't even know where to lay up.
Or you don't lay-up,
and you crush the ball
500 yards over the trees.
Whoa.
[Verne] And Harley clears
the entire forest.
[crowd cheering]
You ain't number one
on this tour, chump. [sniffs]
You smell like my stepfather.
Let's go, Scottie.
Come on, now. Let's shake that off.
[man] You the man, Scottie!
Miss it! Miss it!
[sighs]
[all exclaim]
[Verne] Quite An impressive right cross,
but Scottie Scheffler
is going to be disqualified
before ever swinging a club.
Whoo! That was some gangster shit.
Gangster shit indeed.
There goes the sweep.
Yeah.
Oh, no, not again.
- [officer] Come on.
- [Scottie] I know the drill.
- Bye-bye!
- Sorry, boys.
[Happy] We'll take care of business,
all right?
Next on the tee, Rory McIlroy and Screech.
[crowd cheering]
- [chainsaw whirring]
- [laughs]
Screech?
They call me Screech
'cause that's the sound my chainsaw makes
every time I tear up a golf course.
Isn't Screech a character
in Saved by the Bell?
I'm not familiar with that program.
He was like the comic relief on the show.
Yeah, like the white Urkel.
Nobody cares about that '90s shit!
Those guys do.
I love you, Screech!
- [cheering]
- [laughs]
Let's just play Maxi Golf, all right?
[Verne] The rest of the Maxi team
has no problem clearing the trees.
The regular golfers, not so much.
- [engines start]
- [caddie] Go, go!
[Rory] Hold on! I'm speeding!
[both whoop]
- There it is! Right there!
- Yeah, okay.
Oh, my God. There goes the 8.
[laughing]
[Happy] Shut up!
[yells, laughs]
Here we go! To the right! Whoo!
[both whooping]
- [grunts]
- Yeah!
[8 ball] Looking a little tired, Bry-Bry.
You're looking like
you wanna go for a swim, Davis.
This is the new golf, Bryson,
and it's 8 Ball!
[cheering]
Where's my ball?
Bad shot, Happy.
This'll make you feel better.
How about you take just a sip?
[gulps]
- [burps]
- [chuckles] Wow.
We're doing a breath contest?
Yeah, I'd walk away too, pal.
[Verne] McIlroy's tee shot landed
in the right bunker,
which, like much of this hole,
appears to be on fire.
[yelps, yells]
Screech!
- [both yell]
- [crashes]
[both cheer]
[crowd exclaiming, cheering]
Yeah!
Viva regular golf!
Hey, man. I'm gonna change the channel.
Frankie, sit your ass down.
We're watching golf.
All right. I'm sorry.
Get in the hole.
- [Verne] Oh! Wow!
- [both laughing]
- That's what I'm talking about, baby.
- [crowd gasps]
God damn it, I just washed that.
[Verne] It seems like nothing
is gonna slow Gilmore down.
All right. See you try
and beat this one, Happy.
[man 1] Let's go, Gilmore!
- [man 2] You jackass.
- What the...
- [ball splashes]
- [crowd] Oh!
Are you kidding me right now?
You just cost me the hole, dude!
[laughing] Happy Gilmore.
Man, I wish my father
was here to see this.
Ya jackass.
Jackass.
- Jackass!
- [man] There he is.
Unfortunately... [kisses]
...he's in the great Sizzler in the sky.
Know what? I don't miss that dude at all.
What are you gonna do, Happy boy?
Unless you wanna go to jail,
you can't hit me. Jackass.
Oh, my goodness!
Yeah... but we can.
[Happy] You guys came?
[Donald Jr.] This your posse?
- This is what I do.
- Okay, let's see.
There's only four of you?
Better go get some help!
- [Happy] Okay. Okay.
- [yells]
- Come on! Get him up, boys!
- I know a lot about fighting.
I'll bite your leg off.
You want some smoke? [yelps]
[laughing]
[Donald Jr.] This ain't nothing.
Now you got me really pissed.
Oh, what is this? You want some of this?
Look at the gators!
You brought the whole family. [yells]
Oh, my dick!
Oh! Whoa! Detroit!
[laughing]
I just don't give a--
- [bleeping]
- [muffled shouting]
[all laughing]
Put some respect on my name, bitch.
- What is he doing to those gators?
- Jackass!
Well, it looks like we have
our first fatality.
Whoo!
[Verne] If you can believe it,
the Maxi Golfers
are up two matches to one,
which means Koepka and Gilmore
are going to have to win out
in order to defeat the Maxi team.
[woman] All right there, Flex!
Come on, Flex!
- [ball whizzing]
- [Happy] Boom!
- [woman] Nice shot, hottie!
- Ooh!
No pressure, Boobs Getchya.
[Guy] Next on the tee, Brooks Koepka.
[Verne] To me, the smartest play
is to come up short of the icy green
and give yourself a chance to chip it in.
[crowd cheering]
Yes! Oh, God! [grunts]
Sorry, guys.
I knew I shouldn't have fist-pumped.
[Frank] Sucks for you guys.
- Another disqualification. Game over.
- [team laughing]
No, wait. In the event of an injury,
we have the right to substitute.
All right, fine. Fine.
Who you guys got?
The one and only.
[slurping]
What's that now?
[Verne] And a wild day
just got a bit wilder.
Shooter McGavin will take over
for Brooks Koepka
here on the sixth hole
and the putt from Flex.
Oh, it's off course.
- [yelling in anger]
- I think I see an opening.
Let's go, Scooter! Clock's a-tickin'!
This is a joke.
I'm not a competitive golfer anymore.
What are you talking about?
You still got the shooter in you.
That guy's long gone, Gilmore.
No. He's sleeping.
It's time to wake him up.
Look at these punks. The B-lists.
- Never won shit on the real tour.
- [Shooter] Yeah.
And now they're laughing
at Shooter McGavin,
the greatest golfer of the '90s,
except for me and Tiger?
How dare they?
How dare they disrespect you?
Where should they go?
- Back.
- Back where?
- Back to...
- To their what?
- To their shanties.
- Aha!
Because this is whose tour?
It's Shooter's, Shooter's tour.
- Whose tour?
- It's Shooter's tour!
- It's Shooter's tour, baby!
[mimicking gunshots]
Yeah!
He's got the old pistols back again.
- Give the man his lob wedge.
- Oh, I'm feeling it now.
[Happy] No pressure. No pressure.
[Frank] You're not gonna make it, Shooter.
Tick tock.
- Five, four...
- No!
[Frank] ...three, two, one!
- [crowd cheering]
- You've got to be kidding me!
Oh, my God!
[Verne] Well, how do you do?
Shooter McGavin jars the cup,
wins the hole and his match.
[crowd chanting] Shooter! Shooter!
Come on now! Choke on that!
[Verne] That leaves us tied
with only Billy Jenkins
and Happy Gilmore left to be decided.
And it's come down to this.
The final hole.
Winner take all. The shot clocks are off.
The pressure is on.
The future of regular golf
hangs in the balance.
Thousand-yard par four.
That's a little long.
[Billy] Not for me, big man.
Yeah. Check this out.
Hello?
- Woo-woo! [grunts]
- [whizzing]
- [crowd cheering]
- [Verne] Whoa!
That is the longest drive
I have ever seen.
- Hey, you remember my name now? Bitch.
- [gasps]
I'd like to forget
ever seeing that hip thing.
That was disgusting.
[Verne] Jenkins can be
on the green in two,
while Gilmore has no hope
of getting on in less than three strokes.
Verne, that sucks.
Okay to use that hate one last time, Slim?
Yeah, let it all out.
Ain't no surgery for that.
[man] Come on, Happy, let's go.
You never made the Bruins
because you suck at skating.
You shut your stupid face.
Who's he talking to?
Oh! And your daughter's
never going to ballet school
because her dad's a washed up drunk.
I'm gonna kill you!
[growling angrily]
Uh-oh.
- [yells]
- [screaming]
[screaming, spluttering]
- [groaning]
- [crowd cheering]
[high-pitched voice]
Somebody went further.
Yeah...
- Bitch!
- [crowd cheering]
[Verne] Jenkins is first to hit.
[cheering]
Yes!
Oh, and by the way,
all four of your boys are dumb!
What did you say?
- [Hal laughs wickedly] Ow! Ooh!
- [crowd] Aw.
[Billy] Yeah!
[Verne] I can't believe there's taxis
without drivers,
AI girlfriends, and now, quite possibly,
the end of traditional golf.
[crowd cheering]
[Billy] I'll go first.
Give you a chance to think about
how you're going to play that.
- Whoa!
- [crowd] Whoa!
[laughs] Billy Jenkins,
you stepped on it and stepped in it.
Shut up, Edward Woodenhand.
- Screw you, Cabbage Patch Kid.
- [crowd laughs]
[crowd exclaim]
Take your time.
Go get my lob wedge. Wait.
Go stand right there.
[Billy] Okay.
Right in the back of the cup.
- No, don't get off! God!
- [crowd] Oh!
- Vecsey!
- What?
God damn it.
Excuse me. Know what? You're fired.
Makes sense.
Will you quit messing this up
and make this? Come on.
[Billy] I'm trying, sir.
Just get it on the right line.
[Billy] Coming right up, sir.
[suspenseful music plays]
- [crowd cheering]
- [Verne] And Billy Jenkins is in for four.
- Yeah!
- Choke on that one, Happy!
[Verne] Gilmore has only two shots left
to even tie this thing.
I'm not even playing and my palms
are sweaty. Mom's spaghetti.
I can't get a damn swing off here.
You got any ideas? We're in trouble, dude.
Hmm. I say ricochet that shit.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
- [crowd cheering]
- Amazing!
Did it go in?
Not that amazing.
You nervous?
No, just... Can I use your mailbox?
[Verne] The question now is,
how do you hit on a green
you can't stand on?
[Happy] What do I do?
[Gordy] Here we go, Dad!
- Dad, let's go!
- Let's go! All you!
- [Gordy] Right now!
- All right.
What's the plan?
How about this?
Go to the other side
directly across from me.
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
- Oscar. Hey.
- Yeah, go!
Oh, God, I can't bear to watch.
Oscar, how much do you weigh?
170.
Pick up the bag, please.
Actually, take two clubs out.
Two clubs. Two. Two clubs.
Okay. Pick the bag up again.
And on the count of three,
we're stepping on the green.
- Okay.
- [Happy] Are you ready?
And one, two... three!
Whoa, oh-- Hey...
That's it. That's it.
Okay, we're gonna hop forward.
One. Two. Three.
- [both yelp]
- [Happy] Ooh.
Okay.
Now to the left.
One, two, three.
That's it.
Now we're gonna go sideways... Two, three.
Ooh, Oscar... Nice work.
Check this out.
Whoa!
- What's happening?
- [Oscar] What the...
Sorry, Happy, I had to.
We don't do tiebreakers at Maxi.
How about we raise the stakes?
I end this whole project
if you sink this putt.
And if I miss?
It's simple. You join Maxi League.
[imperceptible]
How about this?
You pay for my daughter's dance school,
buy me my grandma's house back,
plus I get your Rolls-Royce,
plus you gotta buy Oscar
his own restaurant.
What kind of restaurant
are we talking here?
What kind of food, Oscar?
Sushi. No, no, no. Italian.
Fine. You're on.
[Verne] You heard it.
There'll be no playoff today.
Oscar, I have bad news.
I'm holding a sand wedge. I need a putter.
Just take it slowly out of the bag.
That's it. That's it. Take the sock off.
Okay, so we're gonna throw it
to each other on the count of three.
- Okay.
- We can do this.
One, two, three.
- [crowd] Oh!
- Okay. I caught my own club.
Physics is a bitch, isn't it?
Here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna throw it
straight up in the sky.
Let's do this.
Do not get sick, Oscar.
- Okay. One, two, three.
- One, two...
Yes!
Let's go! Let's go, Hap!
High five. High...
Hey, Gilmore can do this.
I've seen it. I lived it.
Wow. Cool.
How bout we take this to the Maxi?
[whirring]
He's gonna fly off.
- ...spot, focus on the spot.
- You got it. Focus.
[laughing]
Oh, no.
Hang in there, Oscar, please.
Come on, Dad. You got it.
[kids] Dad!
[whooping]
- Come on, Dad!
- [cheering]
I love you so much!
Do it like my daddy taught you.
Tap it. Tap it in.
[Verne] It's got a chance.
- Go.
Come on, Happy.
- Come on, come on...
- Come on, come on, come on...
- Get there!
- [crowd exclaiming] Oh!
[Verne] Oh, no!
Yes! Welcome to Maxi, Happy. Whoo!
- [thuds]
- [clatters]
- [ball clatters]
- [all cheering]
Oh, my God! Happy Gilmore has won!
And regular golf will live on.
- I'm 8 Ball! I'm 8 Ball!
- No! That doesn't happen!
You are a piece of shit, you know that?
I did everything I could...
Oscar! We did it, Oscar!
[cheering]
- Papi, papi. Wake up.
- [groans]
- Good job!
- Did we win?
[upbeat music playing over speakers]
- Yes!
- All right!
Happy, yes!
Yeah, yeah!
Stop.
Your training paid off. You did it.
I'm proud of you. I'm proud of you.
- Yes!
What a great win. Let's go to Hooters.
[both grunting]
- Happy Gilmore! Happy Gilmore!
I can't believe I'm saying this,
but you're all free to go.
- [cheering]
- Beautiful.
Unbelievable. Tremendous.
I understand you have a restaurant.
We have the best Italian Dominican
Puerto Rican Cuban restaurant in the town.
[Esteban] I love my new job!
We did it, baby! We did it for Mom!
[all cheering]
Well, I've won a lot of trophies
and jackets over the years,
but out of all of them, I have to say
this is by far the most special.
And I want to thank
all my friends out there
who helped me achieve
this monumental moment.
Three months sober.
[Nate] Yay! Way to go, Mr. Gilmore!
Splendid! Splendid, Mr. Gilmore.
But will you make it to a year?
- Magic 8-Ball says... unlikely.
- Uh-huh.
What are you talking about, Hal?
Happy's going to make it a full lifetime.
Know what else is full, Charlotte?
My gutters. Full of dead leaves
and squirrel droppings.
But you'll be cleaning them out
this weekend.
I don't like the way you talk to that kid.
It's fine, Mr. Gilmore.
No, it's not fine. That kid has helped me
more than you have, Hal.
Seriously, Mr. Gilmore, I got this.
Guys, can we be done here?
We've got enough.
Why are you talking into your collar?
Are you high?
- Holy--
- Whoa!
Hallowicious Lieberman!
You're under arrest
for fraud and extortion.
We got enough footage of you
being a sick son of a bitch
to lock you away for a lifetime.
You narc'd on me?
Guess so.
Hey, man, I was just trying
to help these people.
Manual labor's therapeutically beneficial.
- Hey, Happy.
- What?
- Catch.
- Oh!
[Hal laughing]
- I believe that's Mr. Gilmore's!
- He got my coin!
- [yelling] I got the coin!
- [clamoring]
[laughing]
- [Nate punching]
- [Hal yelping]
- Oh, shit! Stop!
- [Nate] Stay still!
You're a very cool kid.
You're a very cool guy.
You remind me of my dad.
Yeah?
["Tuesday's Gone" playing]
All right, just have fun in Paris.
If you get homesick for America,
I can ship over some Yodels
or bottle rockets.
Whatever you guys want.
We'll be fine, Dad.
And we'll see you next month, right?
That's right.
I got the British Open,
I'll show up a week early, we'll hang out.
I want to see some
fancy French dancing from this kid.
Then you can come check out our show.
What show?
We're gonna be singing mimes.
I thought mimes aren't allowed to talk.
That's how we're gonna separate ourselves
from the other mimes, by singing.
Okay.
♪ We're trapped in a box!
Now we're tugging on a rope! ♪
♪ Even look at our sister... ♪
- And we'll kill you!
- And we'll crush you!
- I'll murder you!
- Don't you look at her!
- Smart. I love that!
- Nailed it. Really good.
Come here. Gonna miss you.
And if you're hungry on the flight,
enjoy the bread from Oscar's restaurant.
Go crush them over there for Mom.
Have a ball.
Love you, Dad.
- Hey, here you go.
- [Happy] You're the best, guys.
- Sir, right there.
- There you go, buddy.
Yeah, get him! [laughs]
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
[Bobby] Come on, Vienna.
Love you. I'll miss you.
♪ Tuesday's gone with the wind ♪
Hey, Happy.
Oh. You're okay.
♪ My baby's gone with the wind ♪
♪ Train roll on ♪
♪ Tuesday's gone ♪
- [car chiming]
- [automated voice] Battery, zero percent.
I didn't charge it! Damn it!
["The Waiting" playing]
♪ Oh, baby
Don't it feel like heaven right now? ♪
♪ Don't it feel like something
From a dream? ♪
♪ Yeah, I've never known
Nothing quite like this ♪
♪ Don't it feel like tonight
Might never be again? ♪
♪ Baby, we know better
Than to try and pretend ♪
♪ Honey no one
Coulda ever told me 'bout this ♪
- ♪ I said yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ The waiting is the hardest part ♪
♪ Every day you see one more card ♪
♪ You take it on faith
You take it to the heart ♪
♪ The waiting is the hardest part ♪
♪ Well, yeah, I might have chased
A couple women around ♪
♪ All it ever got me was down ♪
♪ Then there were those
That made me feel good ♪
♪ But never as good as I feel right now ♪
♪ Baby, you're the only one
That's ever known how ♪
♪ To make me wanna live... ♪
Well, the bad news
just keeps coming for Maxi
and its controversial founder,
Francis Manatee.
Since the spectacular failure
of the Maxi Golf League,
the popular Maxi Sports Drink
has been recalled after complaints
it caused irreversible halitosis,
gingivitis,
and a new condition
they're calling tongue rot.
We at the Sports Hole
tried to reach Manatee for comment,
but his current whereabouts
are apparently unknown.
Yeah, I would run too if I gave
half the world midnight booty breath.
Hey, Scheffler, it's been three days.
You sure you don't wanna make that call?
It depends. What's for dinner?
Chicken fingers.
I'll stick around another night.
Okay.
["Sitting Down Is Stupid" playing]
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Get your biscuits in the kitchen
I'm a sous chef on a mission ♪
♪ Baby, wiggle it, it's vicious
We about to break the dishes ♪
♪ Got the pepper with the sodium
We cookin' with petroleum ♪
♪ Come step up to the podium
And cut up this linoleum ♪
♪ Just move it ♪
♪ Move it ♪
♪ Sittin' down is stupid
Now let me see you move it ♪
♪ Get your peaches off that stoop
Baby, work that hula hoop ♪
♪ Throw it back and watch 'em shoop
Scottie Pippen, alley oop ♪
♪ Mix it up like orange drink
Shake your buffalo chicken wing ♪
♪ Get your galoshes, make it rain
Now-now let me hear you sing, uh ♪
♪ Just move it ♪
♪ Move it ♪
♪ Sittin' down is stupid
Now let me see you move it ♪
♪ Just move it ♪
♪ Move it ♪
♪ Sittin' down is stupid
Now let me see you move it ♪
♪ Sitting is dumb ♪
♪ Dancing is more fun ♪
♪ Sitting is dumb
But dancing is more fun ♪
♪ Dancing is more fun
Dancing is more fun ♪
♪ Just move it ♪
♪ Move it ♪
♪ Sittin' down is stupid
Now let me see you move it ♪
♪ Just move it ♪
♪ Move it ♪
♪ Sittin' down is stupid
Now let me see you move it ♪